The telephone was an amazing invention.
电话是一项了不起的发明。
People could finally speak to each other instantly from one home to another.
人们终于能够足不出户，即刻与彼此对话。
The mobile phone took this technology further, meaning we could make contact with people to and from almost anywhere in the world.
移动电话则将这项技术推向了新高度，这意味着我们几乎能与世界各地的人随时取得联系。
But despite having the instant ability to talk to one another, it seems many of us prefer to communicate by text.
但即便拥有了即时通话的能力，我们中的许多人似乎还是更偏爱用短信沟通。
I don’t mean we have taken up letter writing again.
我并不是说大家又重拾了写信的习惯。
Although a handwritten letter has a personal touch, sending it by snail mail is too slow to satisfy our desire to keep in touch immediately.
虽说手写信件带有独特的个人温度，但平信邮寄的方式实在太慢，满足不了我们即时联络的需求。
But what our smartphones now allow us to do is enable us to communicate in any number of quick, cheap but silent ways.
而智能手机如今能让我们通过多种多样快捷、廉价又安静的方式进行沟通。
A study in the UK a few years ago found 49 per cent of teenagers preferred to send a text rather than speak to someone.
英国几年前的一项研究显示，49%的青少年更喜欢发短信，而非直接与人交谈。
Certainly sending an SMS, text or message via a chat app means we can compose what we want to say, and we can be more efficient in saying it – especially if we express ourselves by using emojis.
毫无疑问，通过短信、文字消息或是聊天软件发送信息，能让我们斟酌好想要说的话，并且更高效地表达——尤其是当我们用表情符号辅助表达时。
It can also be quicker than having to chat with someone, although I feel you can still end up wasting time by having a full discussion by text!
这种方式通常也比实时通话更省时，不过我觉得，要是用短信来展开一次完整的讨论，最终还是会耗费不少时间！
Text messaging also allows privacy – other people can’t overhear your text if you’re in a public place such as on a train.
短信沟通还能保障隐私——当你身处火车之类的公共场所时，旁人不会听到你的聊天内容。
But texting instead of talking can seem antisocial; we may even forget the art of pleasantries.
但只发短信不与人交谈，会显得有些不合群，我们甚至可能会忘掉寒暄的社交艺术。
A text can be misinterpreted too because you miss out on a speaker’s intonation.
短信内容也很容易被误解，因为你无法捕捉到说话人的语调。
Neuroscientist Professor Sophie Scott told the BBC: “We always speak with melody and intonation to our voice… you take that channel of information out of communication, you lose another way that sense is being conveyed.”
神经科学家索菲·斯科特教授在接受BBC采访时表示：“我们说话时，声音里总会带有抑扬顿挫的语调……如果在沟通中去掉了这一信息传递渠道，就等于失去了另一种表达语义的方式。”
Of course texting and talking is the worst thing to do.
当然，一边发短信一边打电话是最不可取的行为。
Who deserves your attention when two people are communicating with you?
当两个人同时在和你沟通时，你该把注意力放在谁身上呢？
It’s then we have to decide who has the most interesting thing to say!
到那时，你就得判断出谁的话更有意思了！